Catalina Romila (PhD)

London, UK catalina.romila@hotmail.co.uk

Summary

Curious mind with attention to detail. Driven, self-motivated, problem-solving attitude and growth mindset. My experiences and training cover a range of fields from science and big data analytics, blockchain basics and cryptocurrency to business innovation, finance, team and project management, all the way through to coaching, and front-end web development.

Skills

- Research analytics
 Communication
 Problem solving attitude
 Critical thinking
- Research skills Data analytics Genomics Data science Coding R CSS HTML
- SQL Python LaTeX Git Cryptocurrency Finance Independent and team-player
- Project planning and management
 Time management
 Decision-making
 IP
- Accelerator /Startup

Education

University - UCL (2015-2019)

PhD – 'High-Throughput Chronological Lifespan Screening of the Fission Yeast Deletion Library Using Barcode Sequencing'

University - Queen Mary, University of London (2012-2015)

BSc in Biochemistry – 1st class with Honours

Experience

Research Scientist: UCL - London (2019 - to date)

Investigative role in characterising endolysosomal pathway genes whose dysregulation is involved neurological diseases like Parkinson's disease. The work is done through manipulation of fruit flies using molecular and biochemical techniques, as well as fly genetics integrated with genomic data analysis. These methods are applied to help develop effective treatments against these types of neurodegenerative disorders.

Transferable skills:

- o Big genomic data analysis i.e. RNA-sequencing
- o Bioinformatics and Analytics
- Time and project management skills
- Presentation and communication skills
- Collaboration skills
- Planning and execution of experimental designs
- o Independent worker and team-player

PhD in Genetics & Genomics of Healthy Ageing: UCL - London (2015-2019)

My project focused on healthy ageing, in particular understanding how the genomic landscape influences cellular ageing in the context of lifespan and longevity. Due to the implications of needing to analyse large genomic datasets, not only I developed a resilient profile, but I quickly became adept in coding and programming, ultimately developing an analytical mindset.

Transferable skills:

- o Molecular techniques i.e. DNA/RNA extractions, RT-qPCRs, gel electrophoresis etc
- o Developing and optimising genetics/genomic techniques and pipelines
- o Genomics protocol optimisation techniques
- o DNA/RNA library preparation, sequencing and data analysis
- o Problem solving and forward thinking
- o Excellent communication, presentation and organisation
- o Resourcefulness, planning and time management
- o Big data manipulation & analysis
- o Coding in R, SQL, Python, GitHub, terminal/Ubuntu,
- o Developer languages i.e. HTML, CSS, LaTeX
- o Proficient in Microsoft Office
- o Teaching and mentoring

Intern: Allen & Overy - London (3 months in 2018)

My role was mainly as a <u>Market Analyst</u> where I was in charge of researching data and presenting it to members of the internal department and to stakeholders. Over time I became experienced, practiced and trained in patenting law with focus on IP exploitation, policy and enforcement.

Transferable skills:

- o Content and market analysis
- o Data compilation and presentation to stakeholders
- o *Intellectual property*
- o Patent infringement strategies

Accelerator Programme Coordinator: IMAGINE!IF - London (2018-2019)

During my role as a Global coordinator for the IMAGINE!IF London accelerator programme I had the chance to further develop my managerial skills by leasing with mentors from different organisations including BioTech giant AstraZenica, overseeing mentor and panel judge recruitment, as well as screening applications and communicating to accelerator participants.

Transferable skills:

- o Global team management
- Effective communication and leasing skills
- o Entrepreneurship
- o Innovation, business and finance acumen

Honours & Awards

Achievement	Issuer	Year
First author scientific article	In review	2020
Web development (Level1)	Softwire	2019
Associate fellowship	Higher Education Academy	2018
Promotion to Global Coordinator	Innovation forum	2018
3 minutes presentation award	LiDO Consortium	2017
Co-author on a scientific article	New Phytologist	2016
Enterprise bootcamp	UCL Innovation & Enterprise	2016
Whittingham award of excellence	QMUL	2015
Student mentor of the year	QMUL	2014
staudite montor of the year	\(\frac{1}{2}\)	2011

Hobbies & Interests

- Cryptocurrency
 Blockchain
 Finance
 Business and Innovation
 Startups
 Health
 Teaching
 Travel
 Languages
 Flags